Pushan Pore

<u>pushan.pore.work@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>My-Website</u> | Kolkata, West Bengal

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Data Engineer working on two projects one in the Azure domain and another in Big Data processing with Splunk. Previously, I worked as a CMDB Data Manager for the NL region at Capgemini. I have total of 2.5+ years of experience in IT. I have expertise in SQL, Python, Excel, and SPL. Also being a 2X Microsoft Certified Azure Data Professional, I'm looking for a immensely data-focused role where I can use my skills in data analysis, visualization, and cloud data solutions for making a real world impact.

EXPERIENCE

Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd.

• Sr. Analyst – Data Engineer

Jul 2024 – Present

Pipeline development using Azure Data Factory | Worked on ETL process for retrieving and storing data in Data Warehouse | Following medallion layer architecture for raw and cleansed data storage | Using SPL and Splunk for processing and transforming big data workloads.

Analyst - CMDB Data Manager

Sep 2022 – Jul 2024

Governed the management of physical and virtual assets for NL clients, ensuring accuracy for over 20000 Assets. Implemented best practices for data accuracy and integrity, reducing anomalies by 80%.

Intern

Jan 2022 – Apr 2022

Full stack developer leveraging Angular and Spring Boot and PostgreSQL.

CodeDrills

• Intern – Interview Problem Setter

May 2022 - Sep 2022

Designed and validated more than 50 SQL and MCQ questions for hiring assessments | Improved assessment accuracy by 50% creating both the question and the test data set for the SQL questions.

EDUCATION

Heritage Institute of Technology

Aug 2018 – Aug 2022

B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering

GPA: 8.73/10

OTHERS

Technical Skills: SQL, Python, Excel, Azure Databricks, PySpark, SPL (Search Processing Language), Splunk.

Certifications: Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900), Microsoft Azure Data Engineer Associate (DP-900), ServiceNow CSA.

Projects:

 Microsoft SQL server data migration from legacy database to Azure data lake storage gen 2, with medallion layer architecture for segregation of raw and cleansed data. Also implemented Data Bricks to process raw data from ADLS Gen 2 and pushed it to data warehouse.